# SAHIL KUMAR

Email: sahil.saini526@gmail.com | Mobile: 0420647144

LinkedIn- sahil-kumar
GitHub- sahilbanait

## **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

I am looking to secure an Android Developer or Front-End Developer position and further expand my skills, knowledge, and experience in a practical and fast-paced environment. Strong collaborator and always willing to complete tasks to a high degree of quality with a positive attitude. Willingness to take on added responsibilities to meet team goals. I am a professional hospitality worker with six years of experience in customer service. I am a recent graduate from Bachelor of Business and a Diploma in software development. I am looking for the right opportunity to bring my customer service skills and continue to grow my knowledge.

### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Business, Murdoch University | 2018 - 2020

Advanced diploma of leadership and management, Cambridge International College | 2017 - 2018

Diploma of software development, Australis College | 2021-2021

ISTQB - International Software Testing Qualifications Board, currently studying

Front-End Developer Bootcamp, Learning People, currently studying

Microsoft Azure Data Fundamentals DP-900 | Sep 2021

Jira Fundamentals | Aug 2021

Oracle database for Developers | Aug 2021

### **PROJECTS**

Personal Portfolio Frameworks: Bootstrap

Programming Languages: HTML, CSS Tools: WebStorm IDE, Node.js

GitHub link: Portfolio

**To-do Application** 

Frameworks: MVVM + Room + Firebase + Jetpack Navigation + Material 3 Design

Tools: Android Studio,

Programming Language: Java

**Asteroid Application** 

Frameworks: MVVM + Room + Retrofit + Coroutines

Description- Gather live asteroid from NASA API using Recycler View

**RESTful API** 

Programming Language: **Kotlin** GitHub link: <u>Asteroid Radar</u>

More personal projects are available in GitHub

### **SKILLS**

# **WORK HISTORY**

# Four Points by Sheraton (Marriot International)

#### Chef

Perth City | Nov 2020 - Current

- · Producing meals according to customer requirements
- Recording temperature in logs sheet
- Stock rotation
- Daily Preparation of food items
- Menu planning with head chef

### Tiamo café

### Chef

Nedlands | June 2017 - May 2020

- Preparing meals according to menu and customer requirements
- Recording temperature in logs sheet
- Responsible for training and supervision
- Stocktaking and rotation
- Daily Preparation of food items

## **Bettys Café**

### Chef

Innaloo | April 2015- March 2018

- Producing meals according to customer requirements
- Complaints and conflict handling
- Training and supervision of new staff
- Recording temperature in logs sheet
- Stocktaking and rotation
- Seasonal Menu planning and Daily Special menu
- Daily Preparation of food items

## **REFERENCE**

Available upon request